Jeff Ashear

Full Stack Developer

Jeff Ashear

Spokane, Washington

303.898.3638

kinesthesiac@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeff-ashear

GitHub: https://github.com/Jeff-Ashear

Portfolio: https://jeff-ashear.github.io/PersonalPortfolio/

Career Summary

Life-long learner with a master's composition, pursuing a full-time position as full stack or front end web development. Experience with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap JS, Jquery, Node, Express, Handlebars, MySQL, MongoDB, and React. Award-winning composer with relevant experience creating object programming-based virtual instruments, sound-sculpture and installations.

Technical Skills

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4 JavaScript, JQuery, Node.JS, Express, APIs, Handlebars, MySQL, Firebase, MongoDB, React, Postman, GIT, GitHub, Heroku, REST, JSON. Logic, MaxMSP, PureData, SPEAR, Ableton Live, Max for Live, cueMix, Audacity. Superior knowledge of music. Proficient researcher.

Applications Built

gamer.Ready: https://jeff-ashear.github.io/gamer.Ready/

- -A fan hub and market research tool, makes persistent commonly searched-for data about released and upcoming games.
- -Creator and Lead Developer. -Full stack work. Uses Javascript, Bootstrap, JQ, ajax, JSON, APIs from RAWG, OGDB, YouTube.

Forager: https://project2player2pt2.herokuapp.com/

- -A food tracking app to help match available ingredients to recipe ideas, and tracks and displays data quantifying and helping to prevent food waste.
- -Front end and UX lead on a team of 5. -Uses Handlebars, Bootstrap, Express, Node.js, Sequelize, JawsDB,

Trivia Game: https://jeff-ashear.github.io/AdvancedTriviaGame/

- -A simple game using dynamic content populated by both timers and user input.
- -Solo project. -Uses HTML5, JQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap, CSS, and GitHub.

Gifytastic: https://jeff-ashear.github.io/GifTastic/

- -A small app that serves up gifs with the click of a button. Users can add their own buttons and store gifs in a favorite list.
- -Solo project. -Uses HTML5, Bootstrap, JQ, JS, CSS, ajax, apis, JSON, and GitHub.

Experience

Self-Employed / Composer

2009 - Present, Denver, CO

Compose and rehearse professionally commissioned musics for small groups of orchestral instruments and active/interactive electronic systems. Pieces performed locally, nationally, and internationally. Developement of custom software tools for making virtual instruments, electronic installations, and specialized sound-sculpture for the concert hall.

Self-Employed/ Classical Guitarist

2005 - 2009, Bozeman, MT

Prepare and perform intricate repertoire for both solo and ensemble concertizing. Teaching students of various ages and ability levels.

Montana State University/ Recording Engineer

1999-2006, Bozeman, MT

Engineer, record, edit, publish, and archive concerts, recitals, and professional studio projects. Experience with studio and concert hall recording equipment and software. Manage complex software and hardware environments.

Education

University of Denver / Coding Bootcamp

November 2019 - May 2020, Denver, CO

Developed my own path of independent study to incorporate digital tools into modern concert music creation. Softwares include Logic, MaxMSP, PureData, SPEAR, Ableton Live, Max for Live, cueMix, Audacity.

University of Denver / Masters of Music, Composition

September 2009 - June 2012, Denver, CO

Developed my own path of independent study to incorporate digital tools into modern concert music creation. Softwares include Logic, MaxMSP, PureData, SPEAR, Ableton Live, Max for Live, cueMix, Audacity.

Montana State University, Bozeman / Bachelor of Arts

September 1999 - June 2005, Bozeman, MT

Specialization in classical guitar performance, recording engineering and composition.

Awards

Multiple competition awards for new works of music 2010-Present.

DU Outstanding Composer, Lamont School of Music, 2011.

DU Playground Commission Award, Lamont School of Music 2011.

MSU Community Service Award, 2005.

MSU Award for Excellence, 2005.